chrobinson.com 2019-12-08

# Privacy Notice | C.H. Robinson — United States

This Global Privacy Notice was updated September, 2019 to provide a more enhanced user experience through the additional of layers and simplified language, and to better explain the different types of cookies used on the website and how visitors can control the cookies placed on their devices. 

This Global Privacy Notice explains how we, the C.H. Robinson group, process personal information obtained via our websites, application software and mobile apps. Click this link to find out more

C.H. Robinson Worldwide, Inc., and its affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively, "C.H. Robinson") respect your privacy. 

This Global Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect, how we use your personal information, with whom we share it, the choices you can make about our use of your personal information and how you can contact us.

This notice is global in nature and describes our data protection practices in relation to personal information collected through our websites, through application software and mobile apps.

References to "website" include CHROBINSON.COM, MYTMC.COM, FREIGHTQUOTE.COM, NAVISPHERE.COM, NAVISPHERECARRIER.COM, CHROBINSON.COM/EN-US/CAREERS, CHROBINSON.COM/EN-UK/CAREERS, and any other website produced, managed, and maintained by C.H. Robinson.

References to “mobile apps” include Navisphere® Carrier Mobile Application, Navisphere Driver Mobile Application, Navisphere Customer Mobile Application and any other mobile application produced, managed, and maintained by C.H. Robinson.

Collapse

We process information about you that you have provided either directly (for example where you have submitted information to us on our websites) or indirectly (for example from publically available sources, trade associations or from the cookie technology we use on our websites). Click this link to find out more

C.H. Robinson collects information about you from various sources. For example, we may have a direct relationship with you, and you may choose to provide personal information to us in connection with that relationship. You may choose to submit information to us, for example, on our websites, in connection with the use of our products, services, or application software, when you participate in an offer or promotion, when you respond to a survey, request white papers, or in connection with an actual or potential business relationship with us. We also may obtain information about you from companies that use our products or services, publicly available information systems, consumer reporting agencies, agents and trade associations, and commercial information services. We also collect information from you when you browse our websites through the use of cookie technology. (See Cookie Statement).

**The types of information we may obtain are:**

Users of Website 

  * Operating system data
  * Weblog data
  * URL Clickstream and path through our website
  * Name and version of your browser
  * Mobile device unique identifier
  * IP Address
  * Website visit statistics

Customers/Shippers 

  * Business contact information (such as job title, department and name of organization) 
  * Contact information (such as name, postal and/or e-mail address, and phone or fax number, country)
  * Third party contact information that support business processes completed on your behalf (such as consignee or transferee)
  * Information pertaining to shipments and delivery (such as origin and destination locations)
  * Business Financial information (such as financial account information used for payment purposes)
  * Usernames and passwords used to access C.H. Robinson resources (such as account registration information to Navisphere Online)
  * IP Address, device ID and statistical information (such as throughput based on use of online tools such as Navisphere Online)
  * Survey responses
  * Social Media identifier(s) (only when you contribute content on our platform)

Carriers/Drivers 

  * Business and contact information (such as name, postal and/or e-mail address, and phone or fax number, country)
  * Financial information (such as financial account information used for payment and credit purposes)
  * Government Identification (such as drivers license or passport)
  * Usernames and passwords used to access C.H. Robinson resources (such as account registration information to our Carrier or Driver Apps)
  * Survey responses
  * Social Media identifier(s) (when you contribute to content on our platform)
  * Geo-location data (such as location data processed via the Navisphere Driver app, and/or information received via in vehicle devices)
  * IP Address, device ID (when using our Carrier or Driver Apps)

Applicants/Potential Employees, Contractors, and/or Contingent Workers 

  * Information necessary to identify potential candidates for employment such as;
    * Professional social media public profile data on professional sites (e.g. LinkedIn).
    * Browsing data from our Careers site (including IP address, website statistics, browsing preferences, clickstream data, etc.) 
    * Contact information
    * Employment application data 
    * Previous employment, education, and industry certifications
  * Information necessary to make employment decisions and onboard new candidates for employment such as;
    * Information required by federal, state, or country laws to enable compliance with jurisdictional requirements such as diversity information, citizenship, etc. 
    * Results of medical evaluations (only where required by law or where necessary for the job role in question)
    * Results of background checks

Employees (Current/Former) 

  * Employment information (Employees can find additional information about our employment data processes and procedures by contacting a Human Resources representative at [HRSC@chrobinson.com](mailto:HRSC@chrobinson.com))
  * Information necessary to identify and onboard new and potential candidates for employment 

Collapse

### How We Use the Information We Collect

We use your personal information for a variety of purposes, but in particular to: provide our products and services, handle your job application, market to you (in accordance with your privacy preferences) and, when you’re using our websites and mobile apps, to keep a record of the pages you have visited so that we can promote more relevant products and services to you. We also make sure that we have a lawful legal basis to use your personal information. Click this link to find out more

**We may use the information we obtain about you to:**

Users of our Website 

  * keep a record of the pages on our website that you have interacted with so that we can better understand your interests and therefore promote more relevant products and services to you; 
  * understand and improve the effectiveness of, and troubleshoot our websites’ and mobile apps’ content, functionality and usability;
  * enforce our websites' and mobile apps’ terms of use; and;
  * provide information you request, such as white papers.

Customers/Shippers 

  * provide information (such as white papers, for example), products, and services you request;
  * provide effective customer service and facilitate payments for services;
  * contact you with special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
  * contact you with information and notices related to your use of our products and services, including our websites;
  * utilize remarketing campaigns using online behavioral advertising techniques;
  * invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
  * improve our products and services and develop new products and services;
  * optimize our business operations (for example, to help us understand best routes so that we can deliver a more effective service); 
  * improve our marketing and promotional efforts (for example, by using technology and social media to help understand whether a particular company may be considering making a transportation decision);
  * understand and improve the effectiveness of, and troubleshoot our application software, websites’ and mobile apps’ content, functionality and usability; and enforce any commercial agreement.
  * provide services that require regulatory oversight (such as customs procedures)

Carriers/Drivers 

  * provide information, products, and services you request;
  * provide effective customer service and facilitate payments or provide credit for services;
  * communicate and coordinate shipment status information such as location and estimated time of arrival;
  * comply with the security requirements of our customers (verification procedures to access facilities);
  * provide insights into shipment characteristics, strategies and allocation of transportation assets; 
  * utilize remarketing campaigns using online behavioral advertising techniques
  * contact you with special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
  * contact you with information and notices related to your use of our products and services, including our websites; 
  * invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
  * improve our products and services and develop new products and services;
  * optimize our business operations (for example, to help us understand best routes so that we can deliver a more effective service); 
  * understand and improve the effectiveness of, and troubleshoot our application software, websites’ and mobile apps’ content, functionality and usability; and enforce any commercial agreement.

Applicants/Potential Employees, Contractors, and/or Contingent Workers 

  * assess suitability for employment and contact you regarding possible employment;
  * process your application and eligibility for employment;
  * to keep you up-dated about future roles that we think you may be interested in.

Employees (Current/Former) 

  * Evaluate your interest in employment and contact you regarding possible employment with C.H. Robinson;
  * Help you, if you are a C.H. Robinson employee, perform your job functions and to manage our workforce;
  * Provide services and benefits to our employees; 

All audiences 

  * promote compliance with applicable legal requirements, industry standards, and corporate policies;
  * promote security to protect against and prevent fraud, claims, and other liabilities and to manage corporate risk exposure; and
  * any other purpose about which we provide notice at the time of collection.

Collapse

### Legal basis for processing

C.H. Robinson will only processes personal information where we have an appropriate lawful basis, for example when: Click this link to find out more

  * we have your consent; or
  * the processing is necessary for our legitimate interests, for example to ensure that our products and services are properly provided, to ensure the security and performance of our network, to promote our products and services; or
  * we need to comply with legal, contractual, and regulatory requirements.

Collapse

### Information We Share

### Data Transfers

We transfer your personal information outside of your home country to countries which may not offer an equivalent level of protection for personal information to the laws of your home country. For example, to the USA. When we do this, we take steps that the law requires to make sure that your personal information is properly protected. Click this link to find out more

When we transfer your personal information to other countries, we will take measures required by the law to protect that information. These measures include data transfer agreements implementing standard data protection clauses.

To obtain more information about the safeguards we have put in place, please contact us using the information below.

Collapse

### Your Rights and Choices

We want to make sure that you feel in control of your personal information and, in particular, to know how you can change your mind if you don’t want to receive our marketing emails anymore. Click this link to find out more

We will offer you certain choices about what personal information we collect from you, how we use that information, and how we communicate with you.

We typically offer you an opportunity to choose whether you want to receive certain communications from us, generally by offering an "opt-in" or an "opt-out" option, depending on applicable law, when you first provide contact information through one of our websites, software applications, and/or mobile apps. In addition, we will include an "unsubscribe" link in each electronic newsletter or promotional e-mail we send you, so that you can inform us if you do not wish to receive such communications from us in the future.

Subject to applicable law, you may have the right to: 

  * request access to and receive information about the personal information we maintain about you;
  * update and correct inaccuracies in your personal information; and
  * have your personal information transferred, blocked, or deleted. 

We will promptly respond to such requests and may ask you for additional information to verify your identity in order to appropriately respond. In most cases, we will provide access and correct or delete any inaccurate information you discover. In some cases, however, we may limit or deny your request if we have a lawful justification. If you would like to exercise any of these rights about your personal information that we hold, please use our contact details set out under the header “How to Contact Us” below.

Please note that there are some instances where we must process your personal information in order to deliver our services. For example, when accepting the terms of use/end user license agreement for our mobile application software, we must collect data from your mobile device in order for software to work properly.

Collapse

### Cookie Statement

C.H. Robinson uses cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies (“Cookies”) to automatically collect information about your interactions, such as browser type, pages viewed, links clicked, and other actions you take in connection with our websites, online ads, and email. Click this link to find out more

**What are Cookies?**

Cookies are small pieces of data (alpha-numerical files) which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website to collect information about your use of the website. Cookies are sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow our websites to remember information about you to make it easier for you to use our websites. Other tracking technologies may use unique identifiers to track and facilitate your use of our websites. 

You can find more information about Cookies and at [https://www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

**Why do we use Cookies?**

We use Cookies for a variety of purposes, including to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, to personalize your experience, to understand how our websites are used, to market our products and services, to measure the success of our marketing campaigns, and for security purposes.

**What Cookies do we use and how long will they stay on your device?**

We categorize our cookies into four types: Necessary, Preferences, Statistics, and Marketing.

Type of Cookie | Purpose  
---|---  
Necessary | Necessary Cookies help make our websites usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The websites cannot function properly without these cookies.  
Preferences | Preferences Cookies enable our websites to remember information that changes the way the website behaves or looks, like your preferred language or your preferred region.  
Statistics | Statistics Cookies help us understand how visitors interact with our websites. They provide us information about the ways visitors use our technology, which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page. The information we collect from these Cookies does not identify you personally but in some cases we may be able to link the information from statistics Cookies to your personal identifiable information.  
Marketing | Marketing Cookies are used to track visitors using our websites and across other websites. The intention is to display information relevant and engaging for you and thereby providing you a more enhanced user experience, as well as to identify future business opportunities.  
Unclassified | Unclassified Cookies are cookies that we are in the process of classifying, together with the providers of individual cookies.  
  
**How to change your preferences so that Cookies are not set on your device**

Most devices allow you to block Cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser. However, if you use your browser settings to block all Cookies (including necessary Cookies, such as those allowing you to log-in) you may not be able to access all or parts of our websites or our websites may not function as effectively. 

For further information about how to block Cookies, please refer to your browser 'help' section or see [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Collapse

### The General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR")

The GDPR requires us to tell individuals some extra information about how we process their personal information. Click this link to find out more

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we process about you is retained for only as long as it is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. After this period it will be deleted or in some cases anonymized.

For more information about the retention periods we apply to personal data please contact us at [privacy@chrobinson.com](mailto:privacy@chrobinson.com).

You have certain rights in relation to your personal information. These include: the right to object to the processing of your information for certain purposes, the right to access your personal information, and the ability to erase, restrict or receive a machine-readable copy of your personal information. We will handle any request to exercise your rights in accordance with applicable law and any relevant legal exemptions. To exercise your rights under the GDPR, please contact us as specified in the _How to Contact Us_ section below. 

You may also have the right to complain to a data protection authority if you think we have processed your personal information unlawfully. If you have such concerns please contact us in the first instance (using the contact details specified in the _How to Contact Us_ section below) so that we can investigate, and hopefully resolve, your concerns.

Collapse

### Use of Our websites by Children under the Age of 16

Our websites are not intended for children under the age of 16. Click this link to find out more

We are proud of our websites and we strive to ensure that they do not offend people of any age. However, unless otherwise noted on a particular site, our websites are not intended for children under the age of 16 years without the permission of a parent or guardian. If you believe that a child has submitted personal information on or through our websites without the consent and supervision of a parent or guardian, please contact us using the information provided below so that we can take appropriate action.

Collapse

### Updates to Our Global Privacy Notice

This Notice describes C.H. Robinson's current data protection policies and practices. We reserve the right to update it periodically. When we do, we will indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated and why the changes were made.

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments about this notice, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, you may contact us using the information below.

**Global Data Privacy Director**  
C.H. Robinson Worldwide, Inc.  
14701 Charlson Road, Suite 1200  
Eden Prairie, MN 55347 United States  
Phone: 952-683-3399

Clicks [here](https://www.chrobinson.com/es-us/privacy-policy/) for Spanish version of the C.H. Robinson privacy notice

Review the C.H. Robinson Ocean Transportation Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Customs Brokerage & Global Forwarding Services Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Domestic Air Shipment Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Global Air Shipment Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Air Quote Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Ocean Quote Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Australia Trading Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson New Zealand Trading Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Canada Standard Freight Forwarding Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Canada Conditions commerciales standards pour le transit de C.H. Robinson Mondial Canada, Ltée

Review the C.H. Robinson Canada Warehouse Trading Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Canada Customs Brokerage Terms and Conditions

Review the C.H. Robinson Canada Conditions commerciales standards pour le courtage en douane de C.H. Robinson Mondial Canada, Ltée 

Review the C.H. Robinson EU Global Forwarding Terms and Conditions 

Review the C.H. Robinson EU Global Forwarding Terms and Conditions - Romanian

Review the C.H. Robinson EU Global Forwarding Terms and Conditions - Spanish

Review the C.H. Robinson EU Global Forwarding Terms and Conditions - French

Review the C.H. Robinson EU Global Forwarding Terms and Conditions - Italian

Review the C.H. Robinson EU Global Forwarding Terms and Conditions - German

Review the C.H. Robinson EU Global Forwarding Terms and Conditions - Polish
